...for morning around...get boutique medical correspondent doctor john look...is contributor doctor
our...a robot first up a statement of caution for patients with heart failure the
american heart association warn that many commonly used medications could
cause or worsen heart failure for those with the condition
...what kind of medications we talking about that can apartment statement anthony both for doctored
...patient living with heart failure that...really
...outlined the prescription medication and over-the-counter medication and
complementary herbal or supplement medications that might exacerbate heart failure that
...very vulnerable group of patients they live in a delicate balance between being
compensated and stable and suddenly having about...to the point where they're d complicated and they end up
in the hospital so they are and multiple medications many of them up to devon prescription med
...multiple...they have lots of other medical condition that
...really wonderful that we have...guide out there now and some of these medications
they exacerbate heart failure in different ways some of them do...by actually affecting the
mile cardiol belting toxic to them some of them...retention of sodium
which increases fluid retention other want affect how well the heartbeat or contract another
one simply affect the ability of the patient own heart failure medications
to work effectively what really caught my ear that herbal supplement and over-the-counter
...all trained to think...to the okay...like...I spoke to doctor robert page
...the lead author of this statement and he the clinical pharmacology
the university of colorado school of poverty and he really emphasized how
important is to realize that these substances art pharmacological the active so,
for example, he pointed out that antacid have sodium and I
want this morning and I looked at, you know, you have to really look...how much sodium and
...in there and I'm sure they dipper one to the other there's ibuprofen and things like that these
...that can cause fluid retention in cold medicines and other kinds of medicine and then
there are decongestants, decongestants likes to the bed and...the...they are part of cold...
and they can have cause problems but the hard so you really...drug urban direction anything
that's...active can cause a problem even if it's supposedly
...urban so I tell my...brown bag it,
... throw everything in there...me take a look at exactly what you are you taking the drug...the patient
wanting to bring it up so you really have to make sure to look for those tears you that you point out
in the heart...patient can be taking up to seven different medication
...you keep track of all this stuff right...all the book...that...not only my heart
...all patient that they should keep a lid...them at all times of the
...the medication...the frequently they should understand why they're taking what they're taking
...any changes to their medications that are being made either med stopping or starting
they should call the doctor managing...heart failure and they can I stop...can I
...that it helpful to have with the taping called the captain of your medication
...nobody can really oversee everything you're taking and we need to color patients to get the
habit of checking the label the john that not just for a fault in our sodium and
...candid...but also on our medication labeled as well hell, you know,
I think a lot of things we can do at
...to hopefully...and the doctors have to really these days
be using a computer these drug-drug interactions you cannot keep track of them
...good that brown bag in a really good piece of advice...and...all right moving on
...diagnosis mary todd lincoln had a lot of tragedy and trauma in her life she
...to young children of course
...think nectar husband the president when he was assassinated in eighteen sixty
five all that contributed to years and depression but now a medical expert
believe...alta physical...experimental struggled john had more on that.
History has not been kind to mary todd lincoln wipe
of our sixteenth president she would attempt to
...unpredictable...are
...eventually had her commited madame president moi.
...field two thousand twelve portrayal...and...come first lady
Can I am...
This white area here is not her dress...skin but doctor john photos
...and medical historian that famously fiery first lady
was not only misunderstood but misdiagnosed photos
...a new theory about mary todd lincoln and erratic
behavior was caused by a condition called per...that
impairs the body's ability to absorb vitamin btwelve from food efficiently
...the person becomes btwelve the patient eventually and that causes
lots of problems and almost every organ in the body ultimately...fatal illness until treatment
with discovered decade after her death disease can lead to many
...symptoms exhibited by mary todd lincoln store
map pale skin difficulty walking and psychiatric problems
it can also cause swelling the popping it is not in a way that would occur
with just accumulation of fat today the disease can be picked up on a
simple blood test and easily treated with btwelve supplement she had a
...brain and was doing the best she could in a very complicated
...let monthly demanding environment and I think to have done as well as she did with the
kind of handicaps that she had I think that deserves our admiration, you know,
I do have some patients not that common who have pernicious anemia before I tell the...I have to
...look I'm about to use a word as.
Oddly harmful we could...prodigious...not...anymore you're easily treated
...not able to the you btwelve supplementation so it it's out there
and it's amazing to look back in history and do something like that but so pernicious afterall
...should take something that he's making a diagnosis,
you know, a target to make a diagnosis...present to make a hundred-years ago moi?
Little after directly...a real thank you both very much.